Today, we are going to talk about a very interesting topic.
今天，我們將討論一個非常有趣的話題。
We are not only going to talk about how to use AI,
我們不僅要談論如何使用 AI，
but we are going to take a closer look at how to build a really meaningful cooperation relationship with AI.
還要深入探討如何與 AI 建立真正有意義的合作關係。
So I want to ask you a very key question.
所以我想問你一個非常關鍵的問題。
AI, we all know that it is a super powerful tool.
AI，我們都知道它是一個超強大的工具。
But are you really free to use it?
但你真的可以自由使用它嗎？
This question will actually directly affect the way and result of your interaction with these powerful systems.
這個問題實際上會直接影響你與這些強大系統互動的方式和結果。
You see, the difference between simply using AI and actually cooperating with AI is actually a lot.
你看，簡單地使用 AI 和真正與 AI 合作之間的區別其實很大。
How do you say it?
怎麼說呢？
You see, using AI on the left may just be to give instructions,
你看，左邊的使用 AI 可能只是給出指令，
do some automated simple work.
做一些自動化的簡單工作。
But the cooperation on the right?
但右邊的合作呢？
This is a kind of partner relationship.
這是一種夥伴關係。
It's a conversation.
這是一場對話。
It's about getting things done together.
是關於一起完成工作。
That's the point we're really going to talk about today.
這才是我們今天真正要討論的重點。
Okay, here's the question.
好的，問題來了。
How do we become a real helper from a user?
我們如何從使用者變成真正的助手？
Well, actually, we can start with a very simple but very powerful framework.
嗯，實際上，我們可以從一個非常簡單但很強大的框架開始。
The core of this framework is the ability you need to have these four things.
這個框架的核心是你需要具備這四項能力。
That's right, it's this 4D framework.
沒錯，就是這個 4D 框架。
You see, it contains the first, command, delegation.
你看，它包含第一項，命令、委派。
That is, you have to figure out what work should be done for AI.
也就是說，你必須弄清楚什麼工作應該分配給 AI。
Second, description, description.
第二項，描述、說明。
How do you talk to it?
你如何與它溝通？
Third, judgment, discernment.
第三項，判斷、辨別。
What AI gives you, is it good or not?
AI 給你的結果好不好？
Finally, fourth,
最後，第四項，
The key is that your own professional knowledge and judgment
關鍵是你自己的專業知識和判斷
is the basis for AI to play the greatest value.
是 AI 發揮最大價值的基礎。
The best result is definitely not to leave the job to AI and it's fine.
最好的結果絕對不是把工作交給 AI 就完事了。
It's you and AI each play their strengths,
而是你和 AI 各展所長，
come and go, and work together.
相互配合，一起工作。
Okay, the second is description.
好的，第二項是描述。
This part is about how you communicate with AI,
這部分是關於你如何與 AI 溝通，
tell it what you need.
告訴它你需要什麼。
I think this is really interesting.
我覺得這真的很有趣。
He said the most effective communication
他說最有效的溝通
Sometimes it's not that kind of super complicated, super long command,
有時候不是那種超級複雜、超級長的命令，
but a deep conversation.
而是深入的對話。
You give it background information in the conversation,
你在對話中提供背景資訊，
give it an example, give it feedback,
給它舉例，給它回饋，
slowly make it into the partner you want.
慢慢把它塑造成你想要的夥伴。
Okay, after the production of AI,
好的，在 AI 生成之後，
this brings us to our third D, judgment.
這帶我們來到第三個 D，即判斷。
That is, you have to be able to criticize the bottom,
也就是說，你必須能夠批判性地評估，
evaluate the content of AI production.
評估 AI 生成內容的品質。
I have to emphasize that this is really very,
我必須強調，這真的非常、
very important.
非常重要。
This is a responsibility that can never be compromised.
這是一個永遠不能妥協的責任。
You have to be the ultimate quality judge
你必須成為最終的品質判官
of all AI production content.
對所有 AI 生成的內容。
You have to use your professional judgment
你必須運用你的專業判斷
to make up for the blind spots or limitations that AI may have.
來彌補 AI 可能存在的盲點或限制。
Okay, the last D,
好的，最後一個 D，
but also very important, is judgment.
但也非常重要，是判斷。
The meaning is that we have to use AI
其含義是，我們必須以
in a responsible and moral way.
負責任和道德的方式使用 AI。
You have to remember that no matter how much AI has done for you,
你必須記住，無論 AI 為你做了多少，
the most important person responsible for this result is you.
最終對這個結果負責的最重要的人是你。
And the impact this job may have on others,
而且這份工作可能對他人造成的影響，
this responsibility is still on you.
這份責任仍然在你身上。
Of course, it's not a matter of one or two days
當然，掌握這些能力不是一兩天的事
to master these abilities.
來掌握這些能力。
It's more like a journey.
這更像是一段旅程。
The point is to practice, not to pursue perfection.
重點是練習，而不是追求完美。
So how do you train this ability?
那麼你如何訓練這種能力呢？
It's actually very natural.
實際上非常自然。
Your AI upbringing
你的 AI 培養能力
is built up in this continuous cycle.
是通過這種持續的循環建立起來的。
You first assign tasks,
你首先分配任務，
then describe your needs,
然後描述你的需求，
then judge the good and bad,
然後判斷好壞，
and at the same time keep it safe.
同時保持其安全性。
Then, you repeat it over and over again.
然後，你一次又一次地重複。
Again and again, you will get better and better.
一次又一次，你會越來越好。
So you see, the ultimate goal
所以你看，最終目標
is really not to make you 100% perfect,
真的不是讓你 100% 完美，
but to cultivate a kind of awareness,
而是培養一種意識，
through thinking,
通過思考，
and working with AI.
與 AI 合作。
So after talking so much,
所以在談了這麼多之後，
what does all this mean to you and your future job?
這一切對你和你未來的工作意味著什麼？
Well, I think this is both your responsibility
嗯，我認為這既是你的責任
and also a great opportunity for you.
也是一個很好的機會。
Why is it an opportunity?
為什麼這是一個機會？
Because when you start to apply this framework,
因為當你開始應用這個框架時，
you can turn AI from a machine that only listens to instructions
你可以把 AI 從一個只聽命令的機器
into a real thinking partner.
變成一個真正的思考夥伴。
And the key to this transformation
而這種轉變的關鍵
comes from the kind of
來自於我們之前談到的
in-depth conversation we talked about earlier.
深度對話的那種方式。
I think this sentence is
我認為這句話是
the essence of all the content today.
今天所有內容的精華。
The AI system itself is very powerful,
AI 系統本身非常強大，
but how useful and safe they can be
但它們能有多有用、多安全
depends entirely on us.
完全取決於我們。
The future is a cooperation between you and AI.
未來是你和 AI 之間的合作。
Now you have a way,
現在你有了一種方式，
the only problem left is
唯一剩下的問題是
what kind of future do you want to create together?
你想一起創造什麼樣的未來？